Okay, so if you're anything like me, as
soon as you start writing a ton of code,
it starts to get hard to process. Maybe
let's look at our array project.html.
Look at all that code. And like
mentally, that's just kind of hard to
process. And so, generally, as a good
practice, you don't want all of your
code to be in one file. In fact, it'd be
really nice if none of these functions
were in this file and we could just use
them because isn't it so much nicer to
just be able to type alert without
having to see up here someone who
defined a function called alert?
Like we don't need to see all the code
to make it work. We just want to make it
run. Well, I've got good news for you.
We can do that with our own functions,
too. So, let's take these functions and
move them to another file. So, let's
command X or control X to cut them
and then save that file and then create
a new file. And we're going to call this
one script.js.
Whenever you put js on the end of a
file, it tells it that it's a JavaScript
file. Which means unlike HTML where we
need to put a script tag to start
writing code, in a JS file, we can just
write code. Write JavaScript code. So
we'd say let my val equal hello. And
just like that, we've created a
variable. Well, let's paste in our
functions here. And then to format them,
hold option shift F or alt shift F if
you're on a Windows. That will
automatically format your code. So now
all of our functions are here in our
script.js file. Um, so let's just save
our file and we'll go see what's
running. And oh no, it says it cannot
find apply to array. And if we look
here, it says apply to array isn't
defined. So it turns out there is one
more step to this. And that is before
your script tag where you wrote your
code, you need to write another script
tag. And here you need to bring in the
file that you just created. The way you
do that is you do src equals and then
you do open quotes and then you say
where is the file on my computer. There
are two ways you could type this. You
could say it's in the C drive in the um
on the desktop or you could use what's
known as
relative references.
So rather than saying here's the exact
location on the computer, it's like um
giving directions from where you are. Um
so we're in test.html.
If we want to get to script.js, where is
it in relation to us? Well, we are in
the same folder. So if we are in the
same folder, then we can just say it's
in the same folder as us. Now let's say
you wanted to go up one folder. Maybe
it's not in array project. It's in the
parent folder. dot dot slash says go up
one folder. So we would be saying from
where test.html is go up one folder out
of array project and into the folder
that holds array project and then look
for script.js.
Um if we don't include that, it just
says look for script.js from where we
are. So if we save this and we come over
to our console, we see that our code
successfully worked. All of our strings
have been capitalized. All of our
numbers have been rounded.
Um, and then I'm going to show you a
couple of caveats, a couple of things
that'll break this. Um, one is that
script tags run in order. Code runs from
the top to the bottom. So, if you use
your script tag down here, it will bring
your functions into your HTML file after
it tries to run this. So if we save it
and we go look at our code, we get to
sorry go look at our running website, we
get to see that apply to array doesn't
exist. The other thing that people are
tempted to try to do is
they will not include that and they will
just in this script tag write a source
and say script.js.
If you do that now nothing is running.
So when you use a script tag you can
only do one thing with it. You can
either bring in information from outside
in which case you would say script
source equals script.js
or
you can run your own JavaScript inside
of it like we have here in which case
you don't put the source tag. If you try
and do both in one script your code will
stop working. So important things if you
move your functions to an external file
then you need to bring that file in
before you call your functions. If you
are bringing in an external file you
must do it in a separate script tag from
the script tag where you write your code
that calls those functions. And that
concludes this video on how to export
your functions to a different file.